Guide to the Yale Miscellaneous Manuscripts Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Numerical, Series II
  - No. 42: Lagerquist, Walter Edwards (1881-1944): TMS (draft), "Causes and Effects of Emigration and Immigration, 1815 to 1860", [1911?] (Box 25)
  - No. 43: Stiles, Ezra (1727-1795): Letter (typescript copy) to Chauncey Whittelsey, 1767 January 20 (Box 25)
  - No. 44: Miller, John Lester (1903-1965): correspondence, 1 photograph, 1924-1960 (Box 25)
  - No. 45: Johnson, Charles Stoddard (1872-1934): certification of passage of freshman class entrance exams, Sheffield Scientific School, and receipt for tuition payment, both signed by George Jarvis Brush, 1890, 1892 (Box 26)
  - No. 46: Langdon, John (1790-1830): ALS to Jonathan Knight, 1812 February 16 (Box 26)
  - No. 47: Reed, Edward Bliss (1872-1940): Transferred to Edward Bliss Reed Papers (Box 26)
  - No. 48: Aiken, Edwin Edgerton (1859-1951): ALS to Robert N[elson] Corwin, 1933 April 15 (Box 26)
  - No. 49: Hart, Henry Harper (-): TMS poem (xerox), "Samuel Flagg Bemis", 1973 September 28 (Box 26)
  - No. 50: Ewell, John Woodruff (1910-): Correspondence, notes, landscape drawings, purchase orders, and other papers relating to the Book and Snake Society garden, 1963-1969 (Box 26A)
    RESTRICTED
  - No. 51: Yale University. Class of 1882S: Transferred to Yale Archives (Box 27)
  - No. 52: Baldwin, Charles Winterfield (1840-1938): ALS to Simeon Baldwin, Circa1848 September 27 (Box 27)
  - No. 53: Seymour, Thomas Day (1848-1907): Transferred to Seymour Family Papers (Box 27)
  - No. 54 Yale University, deed: Transferred to Yale Archives (Box 27)
  - No. 55: Ford, William Ebenezer (1878-1939): correspondence, memoranda, diagrams, legal documents concerning identification of minerals and the Peabody Museum, and concerning publication by Ford, Charles Palache and Esper S. Larson of revised editions of James Dwight Dana's System of Minerology, 1915-1929, undated (Box 27)
  - No. 56: Chittenden, Simeon Baldwin (1814-1889): 5 ALS to Timothy Dwight, Ellsworth Eliot William Lusk, Louis Comfort Tiffany, 1887 January 22-1888 October 26 (Box 27)
  - No. 57: Brooke, Charles Frederick Turner (1883-1946): Transferred to Edward Bliss Reed Papers (Box 27)
  - No. 58: Hendrickson, George Lincoln (1865-1963): address to Yale College chapter of Phi Beta Kappa, memoir on death of Wilbur Lucius Cross, program of the Sather Classical lectures, program of the American Philological Association: Transferred to G.L. Hendrickson Papers, Mss 1272 (Box 27)
  - No. 59: Yale University, deed: Transferred to Yale Archives (Box 27)
  - No. 60: Yale University. Dramatic association: printed menu with 29 signatures on verso, mostly of members of the classes of 1902-1905, menu inscribed "Sir Wm. Honeywood", 1903 April 28 (Box 27)
  - No. 61: Yale University, faculty: TMS petition to the dean by Charles M. Bakewell, Charles A.A. Bennet, John M. Berdan, Gustav Gruener, Fred R. Fairchild, Albert G. Keller, Frederick B. Luquiens, William L. Phelps, Wilmon H. Sheldon, Chauncey B. Tinker, Ray B. Westerfield, Lorande L. Woodruff, 1926 November 25 (Box 27)
  - No. 62: Lovejoy, Allen Perry, Jr. (1882-1918): promissory note to Yale College, account book, invitation to Yale 1904 Triennial Reunion, 1900-1907 (Box 27)
  - No. 63: Holt, Henry Chandler (1881-1955): photographs, correspondence, newspaper clippings, 1902-1955 (Box 27)
  - No. 64: Lyman, Chester Smith (1814-1890): ALS to Almera Bidwell, 1833 October 30 (Box 27)
  - No. 65: Daggett, Stanley (1895-1972): MS notebook for a course with Professors Bakewell and Bennett, MS diary of service in France with Yale Mobile Hospital Unit, photographs, 1917-1918 (Box 27)
  - No. 66: Norton, Howard Churchill (1895-1973): ALS to his mother, 1913 September 25 (Box 27)
  - No. 67: Yale University - History - European War: ALS to Mr. Lynch from the Yale Battalion Christian Association, circular letter to "Mothers of the Yale Artillery Men", 1916 June 26, August 9 (Box 27)
  - No. 68: Sheldon, Joseph (1828-1911): ALS to Charles Winship introducing Edwin A. Smith, 1883 September 17 (Box 27)
  - No. 69: Jacobson, Wendy Nan (-): TM (electrostatic copy), "American Medicine in Transition: The Case of the Yale Medical School, 1900-1920", 1976 (Box 27)
  - No. 70: Blum, John Morton (1921-): 11 student papers on World War II, 1 paper by Herbert G. Nicholas commenting on a paper by Blum, 1963-1974 (Box 27)
  - No. 71: Cofrances [i.e. Cofrancesco], Harry William (1902-1969): Transferred to Harry William Cofrances Papers (Box 28)
  - No. 72: Barton, David Walker (1802-1863): MS notebook on lectures by Benjamin Silliman, and other notes, 1820, 1824, undated (Box 28)
  - No.73: Chapin, Moses (1791-1865): MS notebook containing text of debate, 1811 September 11 (Box 28)
  - No. 74: Rockwell, Alfred Perkins (1834-1903): correspondence with Simeon E. Baldwin, George Jarvis Brush, Baron von Gerolt, Edwin L. Godkin, J.M. Hoppin, Frederick W. Olmsted, Noah Porter, Charles B. Stoughton, S.H. Jay Trumbull, Francis Wayland, poem by James Russell Lowell, autograph album for Yale Class of 1855 with lithographs of students and faculty, 1851-1902 (Box 28)
  - No. 75: Moseley, Nicholas (1898-): ALS to his mother and sister, 1918 December 28 (Box 28)
  - No. 76: Whitlock, Reverdy Robert Hale (1913-): TMS (electrostatic copy), "The Old Brick Row", 1974 September (Box 28)
  - No. 77: McGuinn, Warner Thorton (1862-1937): scrapbook of newspaper clippings re: politics and civil rights, 1901-1918 (Box 28)
    (Microfilmed, 1985 - HM Film 198)
  - No. 78: Bail, Julina N. (-): poem, 1864 November 30 (Box 28)
  - No. 79: Needham, Wesley E. (-): papers and correspondence about his honorary degree; TMS (electrostatic copy), "The Gothic Architecture of James Gamble Rogers at Yale," with foreword, notes, and addenda by George D. Vaill, 1954-1963, 1971 (Box 28)
  - No. 80: Baker, Louis Henry [pseud.]: TMS (typescript) on the history of Yale football, 1825-1947 undated (Box 29)
  - No. 80: Baker, Louis Henry [pseud.]: TMS (typescript) on the history of Yale football, 1825-1947 undated (Box 30)
  - No. 80: Baker, Louis Henry [pseud.]: TMS (typescript) on the history of Yale football, 1825-1947 undated (Box 31)
  - No. 80: Baker, Louis Henry [pseud.]: TMS (typescript) on the history of Yale football, 1825-1947 undated (Box 32)
  - No. 81: Dominick, Gayer Gardner (1887-1961): TMS account of a hunting expedition in New Brunswick, Canada, with 30 photographs tipped in, 1908 September 8-25 (Box 33)
  - No. 82:Webb, Benjamin (1831-1900): 5 ALS from James Hadley, Denison Olmsted, Thomas A. Thacher and Theodore D. Woolsey recommending Webb; record of Webb's acts as an Episcopal priest, 1857, 1868 (Box 33)
  - No. 83: Yale College, oratory: 3 MS documents relating to oratory at Yale College, 1 by Simeon Baldwin, 1 by Josiah Meigs, 1781 Jul, 1784 August 20, 1785 August 25 (Box 33)
  - No. 84: Hill, William Burr (1857-1953): agreement between the Harvard and Yale Football Clubs, signed by Hill for Yale and W.H. Manning for Harvard, 1880 October 13 (Box 33)
  - No. 85: Yale University, faculty judgments: judgments of the faculty on boarding out, leaves of absence, and on the cases of Elisha Moseley, Ezekial Sanford, and others, with correspondence, 1795-1822 (Box 33)
  - No. 86: Platt, Philip Skinner (1889-): TMS memoir (photostatic copy), "The Life with Selected Letters and Poems of Philip Skinner Platt...", 1976 (Box 33)
  - No. 87: Best, Miriam (-): TM (photostatic copy), "The Old Library. Collegiate Gothic in the 1840s", 1976 December 13 (Box 33)
  - No. 87: Cowell, Eugene (-): TM (photostatic copy), "The Trumbull Gallery: The Artist Builds His Own Museum", 1976 December 14 (Box 33)
  - No. 87: Neger, Peter C. (-): TM (electrostatic copy), "The Convergence of National Trends at the Turn of the Century: Carrere & Hastings' Bicentennial Buildings at Yale", 1976 December 14 (Box 33)
  - No. 87: Plunkett, Regina St. G. (-): TM, "Misbegotten Wonder: The Sad History of Osborn Hall", 1976 (Box 33)
  - No. 88: Hamilton, Carl William (-1967): correspondence, bills, and miscellaneous items relating to the Alpha Delta Phi fraternity, the Tyler Trust Association, and the Yale Literary Magazine, 1907-1913 (Box 33)
    - No. 88 (1 of 3): Hamilton, Carl William (-1967): Bus. Mgr. Yale Literary Magazine, 1912-13 (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - No. 88 (2 of 3: Hamilton, Carl William (-1967): Treasurer, Tyler Trust Assoc., 1912-13 (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - No. 88 (3 of 3): Hamilton, Carl William (-1967): Treasurer, Alpha Delta Phi. Papers, 1907-13 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - No. 89: Buckley, Henry Thorp (1813-1882?): correspondence, 1878-1884 (Box 33)
  - No. 90: Raymond, Henry Augustine (1882-1973): MS notebook on physics, 1904 November (Box 33)
  - No. 91: Bishop, Lottie Genevieve (-): business correspondence as Alumni Registrar and executive secretary in Yale School of Medicine and Yale Secretary's Office, 1921-1973, undated (Box 34)
  - No. 92: Ehrich, Lewis Rinaldo [also Louis] (1849-1911): AMS diaries, scrapbook of memorabilia, obituary
    (transferred to Louis R. Ehrich 1865-1869, Papers, MS. No. 1349), 1911
  - No. 93: Van Brunt, Elmer Willis (1882-1950): correspondence, class exercises, notebooks, and memorabilia, 1897-1901 (Box 35)
  - No. 94: Oren, Dan A. (-): TMS (electrostatic copy), "Jews at Yale - A Preliminary Examination", 1977 (Box 35)
  - No. 95: Ward, George Ligget (1875-1954): MS notebook of a course probably with William Lyon Phelps, [1897 October 26-1898 April 26] (Box 35)
  - No. 96: Roberts, Gary Boyd (1943-): (Box 35)
    see Mss 124
  - No. 97: Olmsted, Denison (1824-1846): MS commonplace book with brief autobiography, diary entries, and notes, [1838-45] (Box 35)
  - No. 98: Goodspeed, Edgar Johnson (1871-1962): TLS to Howard Spencer Colwell, 1951 July 5 (Box 35)
  - No. 99: Jones, Frederick Sheetz (1869-1944): TLS to Mrs. William A. Taylor, 1917 March 20 (Box 35)
  - No. 100: Williams, Chauncey Pratt (1902-): correspondence during his service in the U.S. Army, 1942-1943, 1954 (Box 35)
  - No. 101: Sheffield, Edward Chase (1838-1861): journal; book of notes and sketches from courses with Denison Olmsted and Chauncey A. Goodrich; class album of autographs and engravings of students, faculty, and Yale College, 1857-1958 (Box 36)
  - No. 102: Le Conte, Porter (1817-1847): 19 ALS to his family, partial genealogy and 1 newspaper clipping, 1838-1845, 1878 (Box 37)
    Letter to "Mother" on January 1840 transferred to folio container. See: Folios, Box IV.
  - No. 103: Grant, William (1810-1830): correspondence and miscellaneous items, 1819, 1827-1831, undated (Box 37)
  - No. 104: Phenix, Paul Stetson (1894-1972): 3 expense books, 1912-1916 (Box 37)
  - No. 105: Yale University. Class of 1908: correspondence of the Executive Committee of the class, especially John Ellis Knowles and Louis L. Hemingway, of other class members, and newspaper clippings, 1968-1969 (Box 38)
  - No. 106: Edwards, Jonathan Walker (1772-1831): ALS to Benjamin Trumbull, Jr., with autograph notes [by Trumbull?], [1785] November 30 (Box 39)
  - No. 107: Trumbull, Benjamin (1735-1820): MS account of a difficulty between the Junior and Senior classes at Yale College, [1758] (Box 39)
  - No. 108: Smith, Russell (1822-1866): Transferred to Album Collection (Box 39)
  - No. 109: Gee, John Archer (1894-1944): MS notebook of exercises in Old and Middle English, MS review of The Literary Magazine, 1919, [1936] (Box 39)
  - No. 110: Yale Anthropology Club: minute book and correspondence, 1901-1917 (Box 39)
  - No. 111: Berkeley, George, bp. of Cloyne (1685-1753): correspondence on the picture of Berkeley painted by John Smibert, by John Davis, Chauncey A. Goodrich, Edward C. Herrick, and Evert A. Duyckinck, 1815-1855 (Box 39)
  - No. 112: Kingsbury, Oliver Addison (1839-1914): TLS to his father, 1859 September 17 (Box 39)
  - No. 113: Noss, Luther (1907-): TMS (electrostatic copy), "The History of the Yale School of Music. A Condensed Chronological Summary, 1848-1970", 1979 March (Box 40)
  - No. 113: Noss, Luther (1907-): TMS (electrostatic copy), "The History of the Yale School of Music. A Condensed Chronological Summary, 1848-1970", 1979 March (Box 41)
  - No. 114: Griswold, Arthur Sheldon (1896-): reminiscences of the Yale Class of 1918, undated (Box 42)
  - No. 115: Livingood, J S. (-): ALS to John K. Burns, 1849 October 14 (Box 42)
  - No. 116: Dodge, David Stuart (1836-1921): account book, 1854 September 15-1857 August 3 (Box 42)
  - No. 117: Little, Walter Hale (-): diary with programs and memorabilia laid in, 1881 July 12-1882 March 9 (Box 42)
  - No. 118: Williams, William Minor (1824-1852): MS notebook kept by Williams and Delos W. Beadle, Circa1842, 1870 (Box 43)
  - No. 119: O'Connor, Caleb W. (-): MS song, "Down the Field," to music by Stanleigh P. Friedman, signed by O'Connor and Friedman (transferred to Yale Misc Mss 133), 1904 (Box 43)
  - No. 120: Woodbridge, Dudley (1778-1853): MS account book [1794] (Box 43)
  - No. 121: Hubbard, Stephen Grosvenor (1816-1905): 3 ALS (Ms copies) to President Porter, U.S. passport, report of the Committee of the Medical Faculty on a Gynecological Clinique, protest to the Corporation of Yale University, reply to request of his colleagues for resignation of his professorship, addresses at the induction of President Dwight of Yale, 1866, 1877-1880, 1886 (Box 43)
  - No. 122: Wheeler, Wilson Curtiss (1857-1928): AMS, "Problems in Practical Astronomy," with laid in letter from Elias Loomis, [1879 Sep] (Box 43)
  - No. 123: Bemis, Louis Sylvester (1846-1900): correspondence to his family, bills, 1863 November 1-1868 December 8 (Box 43)
  - No. 124: Roberts, Gary Boyd (1943-): MS (electrostatic copy), genealogy of Yale University presidents, beginning with A. Bartlett Giamatti, [1978] (Box 44)
  - No. 125: Tsai, Stephen I-O (1900-): MS account of his imprisonment by the Japanese in Peking, related correspondence of George S. Franklin, 1941-1948 (Box 45)
  - No. 126: Porter, Jacob (1783-1846): correspondence, poetry, scientific drawings, certificates, 1806-1831, 1847 (Box 45)
    See: Series III
  - No. 127: Walker, Ethel Childe (-1885): MS notebook, eulogy by Josephine M. Lewis, 1886, undated (Box 45)
  - No. 128: Hubbard, George Henry (1855-1928): MS diary, with 2 letters laid in (transferred to George H. Hubbard Pps, MS. NO. 965), 1897 January 1-1898 January 1 (Box 45)
  - No. 128A: Morgan, Harrison Pratt (1908-1944): correspondence, MS journal, printed matter, 1941-1944 (Box 45)
  - No. 129: Root, Samuel (1789-1868): MS commonplace book, 1812 (Box 45)
  - No. 130: Robertson, John Brownlee (1809-1892): MS commonplace book, 1827-1829 (Box 45)
  - No. 131: Stevens, Frank Burton (1861-1946): ALS from Thomas A. Thacher, ALS from Robert Appleton, 1879 August 16, 1884 January 7 (Box 45)
  - No. 132: Friedman, Stanleigh Pohly, (1884-1960): portfolio of mounted clippings, programs, royalty statement for 1906 and "original pencil notes" of the Yale song, "Whoop it up," composed by S.P. Friedman, with words by Caleb Henry O'Connor. Included also is a copy of the sheet music for "Down the field," by Friedman and O'Connor, published in New Haven in 1904, 1904-1920 (Box 46)
  - No. 133: O'Connor, Caleb Henry: Down the field. March by S.P. Friedman. Words by C.H. O'Connor, 1904 (Box 46)
  - No. 134: Yale University - Students: 7 ms notebooks kept by an unidentified Yale student from eastern Connecticut. Included is one account book for his freshman year (1800), four books with notes on sermons, one on mathematics and one on philosophy of Duncan and Locke, 1800-1804 (Box 47)
  - No. 135: Hôpital Général de Montréal, International Symposium on Preventive Services in Primary care, Circa 1919 (Box 47)
  - No. 136: Withington, Leonard, (1789-1885): Ms, A dialogue in two acts, written for exhibition at the public commencement of Yale College in 1814 (Box 47)
  - No. 137: Hinman, William Lamson, (1833-1899): Personal and business letters, essays writeen while at Yale College, two notices of disciplinary action at Yale (1851, 1852), and a notebook with accounts (1845-1846) on the estate of C.W. Hinman. The letters (1851-1856) are largely from classmates at Yale and include Andrew D. White, Edward W. Seymour and Edward Harland. The business correspondence dates from 1864 to 1869. There are also three letters from his mother. Of particular interest is a letter (1855 Jan 17) from R. Bushnell and Frederick William Evans, two Shakers, describing the principles of their community, 1851-1869 (Box 47)
  - No. 138: Jenkins, Edward Hopkins (1850-1931): Ms notebook kept by Edward H. Jenkins listing the members of his class, their class divisions, team standings, honors, awards and society memberships, 1872 (Box 47)
  - No. 139: James, William Knowles (1852-1927): Ms notebook containing his diary and daily accounts for living expenses, 1874 December-1876 January (Box 47)
  - No. 140: Kingman, Edward Lyman (1871-1936): Papers, 1894-1919 (Box 47)
  - No. 141: Eldred, George, Everitt, compiler: Ms notebooks with vital statistics and causes of death of Yale graduates, 1859-1914 (Box 47)
  - No. 142: Joy, James Richard (1863-1957): TMS (carbon) log of the yacht, Hyac, on a fishing trip in the Great Lakes by five members of the class of 1885, 1916 July 31-August 13 (Box 48)
  - No. 143: Delano, Moreau (1877-1936): Ms notebook, "Our visitors book! 62 Vanderbilt. 1898-1898" kept by Moreau Delano and Marshall Jewell Dodge (Box 48)
  - No. 144: Hewes Davis (1824-): Chiefly letters from David Hewes to his mother of which eight are from him when he was at school at Andover (1844-1847) and nine from Yale College (1847-1849), 1842-1861 (Box 48)
  - No. 145: Simison, Barbara Damon: TMS, "Information about the Yale lots in the Grove Street Cemetery. Assembled by Barbara D. Simison of the Reference Staff of the Yale University Library, 1944 (Box 49)
  - No. 146: Leonard, Charles Henry (1841-1938): Ms account book kept while a student at Yale College, 1861-1865 (Box 49)
  - No. 147: Graham, Richard Crouch (1739-1771): Ms commonplace book including sermons, religious meditations, poetry and a family genealogy. With notes made by other after death of Richard C. Graham. (Box 50)
  - No. 148: Hendrie, Hannah Maria (Lockwood) (1793-1849): Typescript copies of letters to John W. Hendrie from his mother, Hannah Marie (Lockwood) Hendrie while he was a student at Yale College, Also one letter from his father Charles Hendrie dated Jul 18, 1864. With a typescript biogrpahy of John W. Hendrie, "Letters to John," by Mabel L. Hendrie, his grand-niece, who also annotated the letters, 1847-1849, 1864 (Box 50)
  - No. 149: Hough, Addison Hills(1869-1935): Correspondence with classmates (1890 Jul 2-1891 Jan 6) largely relating to his activities as Business Manager of the Yale Glee Club; a notebook of accounts for the Junior Promenade of 1890, for which Hough served on the committee, and a notebook with entries on astronomy, Greek and also containing verses for Glee Club songs, an essay and poetry, 1890 July 2-1891 January 6 (Box 50)
  - No. 150: Butler, Daniel(1808-1893): Scrapbook and letterbook of Daniel Butler, minister and secretary of the Massachusetts Bible Society. Included are ninety-one autograph letters (1837-1892) relating to his professional life and newspaper clippings, ca. 1857-1878 (Box 51)
  - No. 151: Fitch, John (1783-1845): Diary (1801-1802), commonplace books and notebooks kept by Fitch while a student at Yale College. Included are several of his compositions, notebooks on disputations, law notes and his extracts from Hume and Blackstone's Commentaries, 1801-1803 (Box 52)
  - No. 152: Murray, William D.,(1858-1939): 188 ALS to his friend, James Parker, in Plainfield, New Jersey describing his life as a student at Yale College, with any references to sports. Also included is a cash-book for his expenses while at Yale College, 1876-1880, 1876-1881 (Box 53)
  - No. 153: Walker, Horace Dean(1815-1885): Ms autobiography of his life until ca. 1856 transcribed by Edward Washburn Hopkins, Circa 1856 (Box 54)
  - No. 154: Worcester, Dean Kirkham (1922-): TMS (carbon copy) East Sussex landownership. The structure of rural society in an area of old enclosures, 1733-1787 (Box 54)
  - No. 155: Ray, Harold Lloyd(1929-): 2 TMS (carbons) relating to William Gilbert Anderson: "The life and professional contributions of William Gilbert Anderson, M.D." 1959, "Chautauqua - W.G. Anderson's early showcase for physical education,", 1959, 1962 (Box 54)
  - No. 156: Willis, Nathaniel Parker (1806-1867): ALS to J.C. Odiorne at Yale College with news of Andover, 1822 (Box 54)
  - No. 157: Common-place book with philosophical and religious entries. Yale College, 1825 (Box 54)
  - No. 158: Elliot, Henry Rutherford(1849-1906): 2 ALS to Henry R. Elliot referring to his ancestor, Samuel Russell, in whose study Yale College was started, 1901 November 1, undated (Box 55)
  - No. 159: Davis, Luther Berryhill(1916-): TMS, "Bail for Yale!" The first draft of the dialogue for a musical comedy... by Luther Berryhill Davis and A.J. Waring, Jr. With 3 unsigned copies (typescript) of a contract with the Lily Guilders to produce "Bail for Yale!" (1936 Dec 5) and newspaper clippings relating to the banning of its production on Yale campus (1936 Dec), 1936-1937 (Box 55)
  - No. 160: Hurd, John Codman (1816-1892): Miscellaneous research materials relating to Codman's books on American history, including a letter (1890 Sep 19) from Judge H.F. Simrall of Jackson, Commenting on his book: The Union State (Box 55)
  - No. 161: Kökeritz, Helge (1902-1964): Miscellaneous professional papers, including reading lists and examinations for courses at Yale University and essays on linguistics by Kökeritz and others, 1942-1955 (Box 55)
  - No. 162: Shepherd, John W.(-1894): ALS from John W. Shepherd, to Charles Shepherd, 1842 April 18 (Box 55)
  - No. 163: Severinghaus, Sarah Claassen: TMS (electrostatic copy) "A biography of my grandfather, Frank Strong, Chancellor University of Kansas 1902-1920" (Box 55)
  - No. 164: Whittelsey, Samuel (1686-1752): Ms notebook with his comments on John 17:3, 1711 (Box 55)
  - No. 165: Grube, Franklin (1831-1869): Ms notebook with copies of his compositions and speeches at school (1841), at Dickinson College (1848-Mar 1849), at Yale College (Oct 1849-1852). Also a copy of a thesis, "Abuse of tobacco," submitted to the Medical Faculty, University of Pennsylvania (1854) and miscellaneous essays and addresses, Clinto, Mississippi (1854-1856), 1841-1856 (Box 55)
  - No. 166: Blagden, George Washington (1802-1884): Ms notebook, "Desultory observations, No. 8", 1826-1828, 1848-1853 (Box 55)
  - No. 167: [Miller, George?], compiler: Album with "Extracts concerning Yale from The New Havener vol.III (1837-1838)." With two pages of accounts (1860) at the end, 1837-1838, 1860 (Box 55)
  - No. 168: Yale University. Dept. of Physics: Ink drawing of an "Air pump," possibly used in the department of Natural and Physical Sciences at Yale College. Two ms sheets, each titled: Table for the Micrometer, 1783, circa 1805 (Box 55)
  - No. 169: Huntington, George, Jr.(1807-1828): ALS to his cousin, Benjamin N. Huntington, at Rome, New York describing the city of New Haven and life at Yale College, 1826 October 20 (Box 55)
  - No. 170: Patton, John (1850-1907): ALS to Miles W. Tate of Tionesta, Pennsylvania with observations on current events and life at Yale College, 1873 November 2 (Box 55)
  - No. 171: Twistle, Timothy, Pseud. Ms, "Farrago libelli or the speculations of a Sophomore. No.1 By Timothy Twistle, Principal Editor", Circa1830 (Box 55)